Guide to the Employee Unions and Strikes, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Employee unions and strikes, Yale University, records
1968-2008
RU 105
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.25
The records consist of flyers, news clippings, posters, buttons, and a videotape documenting union organizing activities and labor strikes at Yale University.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 36 (YRG 36), Records of Yale labor organizations
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transfers and gifts from various offices and individuals, 1984-1996
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of flyers, news clippings, posters, and buttons documenting union organizing activities and labor strikes at Yale University
Industrial relations; Labor disputes; Labor unions; Strikes and lockouts; Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Labor unions; Federation of University Employees; Yale University -- Employees
- Strike posters, Accession 19ND-A-154
  - Strike Posters (Box 1)
- Transcript of Phil Donahue Show filmed at Yale during Local 34 strike, 1984; Accession 1985-A-064
  - Transcript from the Phil Donahue Show filmed at Yale during Local 34 strike. Guests: A. Bartlett Giamatti, John Wilhelm, Lucille Dickess, 1984 November 6 (Box 1)
- Printed materials and clippings concerning Local 34, Federation of University Employees, 1968-1985; Accession 1987-A-027
  - Pre-union
    - Association of Clericals & Technicians (ACT), circa 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Yale Non-Faculty Action Committee (YNFAC), 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Local 35, AFL-CIO-Contract negotiations letter to A. Kingman Brewster, 1974 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Agreement between Federation of University Employees, Local No. 35, AFL-CIO and Yale University,", 1980 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - United Automobile Workers (UAW)--Technical, Office, Professional Department: Union Drive, 1980 September 30-1981 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Local 34
    - Union Organizing Committee, 1981 February 27-December 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Organizing Committee Booklet, Circa 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Union organizing, 1982 January 17 - November 30 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Union drive, 1983 January - July (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Contract negotiations
      - 1983 August-November 15, 1984 January 5-Mar, 1984 April 10-August (Box 1, Folder 10-13)
  - Strike
    - Strike warnings, pre-strike material, 1984 September (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Strike announcements, bulletins, 1984 September 26-28 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Strike begins: general literature, organizing material, 1984 September (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Strike bulletins, Union information, 1984 October 1-30, 1984 November 7-29 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - "Yale and Local 34: Facts on the Current Dispute", 1984 November 29 (Box 2, Folder 19-21)
    - End of the strike: negotiations and settlement, 1984 December-1985 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Memorabilia: Local 34 Support Buttons (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Memorabilia: picket signs, posters (Box AF8)
  - The Administration's Perspective, 1968-[1983-1985]
    - Administration's position on unionization, 1968 May 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Strike negotiations, 1971 March 26-April 30 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - University position on fact-finding (Local 35), 1974 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Strike negotiations, 1977 October 19 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - UAW unionization retaliation, 1981 October 7-February 10 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Administration's position--Union drive, 1982 April 30-December 9 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Administration's position--"Another Viewpoint,", 1983 January 7-April 4 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Yale University: "Election Fact Book" (#1), 1983 April 4 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Another Viewpoint" series, 1983 April 18-May 4 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Yale University: "Election Fact Book #2,", 1983 May 6 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Another Viewpoint" series, 1983 May 11-16 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Contract negotiations with Union, 1983 March 18-December 21 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Contract negotiations with Union, 1984 January 17 - February 27 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Reaction to strike threat, 1984 March 3-29 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Administration's contract proposal (1984 Apr 18) and repercussions, 1984 April 4 - May 9 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Reaction to strike threat, 1984 May 16-17 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Negotiations, contract modification, 1984 June 7 - September 7 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Reaction to strike threat, 1984 September 17 - 24 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Strike: The Administration's Position, 1984 September 26-30 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Administration and the strike, 1984 October-November (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
    - Report to Yale University by Professors Fiss, Goldstein, & Marshall, 1984 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Contract agreement, 1985 January 25 - May (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "Agreement between Yale University and Local 34, Federation of University Employees,", 1985 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Reactions and Opinions of the Yale Community, 1970-1984
    - Pre-union--"Yale Break: A Newspaper by and for Women,", 1970 February 10-1971 January 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Anti-union literature (by C & T's), 1983 Spring (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Anti-union literature, 1984 March (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Faculty and student opinions (pre-strike), 1984 March 16 - September 24 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Faculty & student opinion during strike, 1984 September - October (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Yale community opinion on strike issues, 1984 October 2 - October 13 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Teach-in (Concerned Faculty and Students), 1984 October 17 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Yale community opinion on strike issues, 1984 October 21-24 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Sit-in at Sterling Library (students), 1984 October 24 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Yale community opinion on strike issues, 1984 October 25-31 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Yale community opinion, rallies, moratorium information, etc., 1984 November 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Rally for Reconciliation, 1984 November 12 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Moratorium, 1984 November 14-16 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Yale community opinion on strike issues, 1984 November 15-16 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1982-[1984-1985]
    - 1982 January 19 - February 8 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1983 May 2 - 1984 January 27 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1984 February 9 - February 28 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1984 March 2 - March 31 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1984 April 1 - July 30 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1984 September 2 - September 30 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 1984 October 1 - October 14 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1984 October 15 - October 28 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 1984 November 1 - November 18 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 1984 November 19 - November 30 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 1984 December 1 - December 30 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 1985 January 3 - February 13 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Newsclippings of Local 34 Union articles, 1977-1985; Accession 1994-A-048; 2; (2 boxes) (Box 1–2)
- Miscellaneous materials concerning finances and strikes, local 34 and 35 and GESO, Circa 1988-2000; Accession 1998-A-119; 0.5; (1 box) (Box 1)
- President Richard C. Levin face masks, 2002; Accession 2003-A-093
  - President Richard C. Levin face masks, 2002 (Box 1)
- Locals 34 & 35 strike placecards, 2003; Accession 2004-A-039
  - Locals 34 and 35 strike placards, 2003 (Box 1)
- "I Support Yale Workers," button, 2003; Accession 2004-A-043; 0.5; (1 box) (Box 1)
- Buttons worn by workers and supporters during 1984 strike, Accession 2004-A-072; 25; (1 box) (Reel 1)